How would you feel
if you made a
video and it could
have made you a
million dollars, but you
didn't do a couple
of things in it,
so it ended up
making you none? Not
good, right? Well, I
wasted years and over
30 million views making
content that didn't earn
me the money I
could have, because back
then I didn't plan
videos with any goals
other than getting more
views. And I just
thought, oh, that'll eventually
grow the business, which
it did. But when
I made this video
years later, I realized
how dumb I'd been,
because RevTrack showed me
that what I say
in a video and
when I say it
and the type of
content I make and
the stories I tell
have a massive impact
on sales and email
signups. And after realizing
this, I started to
design my videos, so
I either grew the
business or grew the
business. What that meant
was this 10 out
of 10 flop got
hardly any views, but
it's my number one
video for getting emails.
So it was a
massive hit. This one,
it's made like $250
,000. And got... Thousands
of emails. This one
made $3 every time
I got a view.
And it's all because
I started optimizing each
video for a clear
goal instead of guessing.
So in this video,
I'm going to show
you exactly how to
do that too through
something called conversion optimization.
You're going to learn
how to plan videos
for sales and emails
so that eventually every
video, no matter what
views it gets, earns
you money or leads.
And that makes this
so much easier to
remove the emotion from.
So what is conversion
optimization exactly? Well, most
people post videos with
no plan, no goal.
No way to measure
success and then wonder
why nothing's working. But
when you plan each
video around a clear
business outcome, everything's so
much easier to track.
You know what success
looks like. You can
build towards it. You
can measure it. You
can actually improve it.
So conversion optimization is
just saying, okay, I
want this video's main
goal to be emails.
And then you do
certain things in it
to make it happen.
So now I'm going
to show you exactly
how to optimize your
videos for email sales
and views. So you
always know what you're
building each video to
achieve. So the first
thing you do is
you're going to do
a lot of optimization.
And you're planning any
video is you just
pick a goal. Every
video has to have
a primary one, sales,
emails, or views. Now
you can add a
secondary one. So you
could say, and then
I want emails and
sales too. Or you
could try optimizing for
all three, but that's
going to add complexity
fast. So I only
ever pick one I'm
interested on and any
of the others are
a bonus. If you're
a new channel, you
have to just optimize
for views first because
you need attention before
you can convert it.
The system ain't going
to work without it.
Then step two, you
optimize for views. Then
step three, you optimize
for your goal. So
let's start with how
to optimize for email
signups. Now the easiest
way to do this
is like this. So
if you want to
get maximum clicks on
your email signup and
really high conversions, use
a lead magnet that
is aligned with the
video's topic and the
steps and your offer.
All right, so this
first AI is free.
You can access it
from the link in
the description. And what
it's going to do
is this. So in
about two minutes, it
will tell you exactly
what to put in
your next video, so
that it stands more
of a chance of
breaking down your email.
And it's going to
do that based on
what your viewers have
said about similar videos.
So things like what
they love, what they
hated, what confused them,
what questions remained unanswered.
And then it's going
to give you a
step by step guide
telling you exactly what
to put in your
video to give them
absolutely everything they loved
and a bit more.
What that means is
you can just stop
guessing about what to
include and just make
what's in demand faster.
So you can see
what is sped out
on the screen right
now. Feel free to
pause it and give
that a read. It's
flipping amazing. So in
that example, I basically
made a tool I
used in the content
and then said, if
you want it yourself,
you can download it
in the link below.
Now, it's not always
an option to do
this every time. And
we don't want to
spend forever building lead
magnets, but that would
be my long -term
goal. But if I
really want signups, that's
the best way to
do it. Now, the
next golden rule, if
you want maximum signups
for video, is to
mention your email signup
three times. Early in
the video, usually the
first 90 seconds, after
a point lands, and
then at the end
too. If you do
this, you see link
clicks shoot. Then you
just put the email
signup as the top
link below your video,
and then put it
as the top link
in your comments and
pin it. And then
the final rule is
just to keep your
call to action in
the video short and
say, oh, by the
way, you can grab
this tool in the
link below. Do not
go on longer than
it needs to be.
Now, there's a module
in the advanced section
on lead magnets, but
don't offer a free
course. These are awful
for getting people to
actually sign up something
versus just a simple
checklist or a tool.
Don't offer something that's
misaligned with your positioning
statement. And remember, this
chart from phase one,
our email signup needs
to solve the same
problem for the same
person. If it doesn't,
your sales system breaks
and also don't build
something that takes months.
This has just got
to be kept simple
as we test to
try and find the
best lead magnet we
will then use over
and over again over
time. All right, so
now let's look at
how to optimize a
video for sales. So
there's a few strategies
here. We have obvious
selling and stealth selling.
So let's look at
obvious selling to start.
So obvious selling is
when you make a
very direct pitch. Like
if you want to
grow your channel five
times faster using a
proven system, click my
link below. And the
best practices here are
you need to expect
some push pack from
viewers. They're not going
to like it. That's
normal. But just remember
you're running a business,
not begging for views.
You want to pitch
fast. You want to
pitch after value to
convert more cold viewers.
You want to pitch
early in the video.
The earlier, the more
people will see it.
And you need to
put the sales page
signup as the top
link below your video
and then the top
link in your comment.
So that that is
the one that sticks
out fast. And then
option two, stealth selling,
which is until this
point, the only thing
I've ever really done.
So stealth selling is
selling without people realizing
they're being sold to.
And the key to
doing this is to
start with a mindset
shift and realize that
every video you make
is an advert, even
if you're not promoting
anything anyway. So don't
be afraid of doing
this. And here's how
I do it. So
the first thing I
always try and do
is use client stories
in my intro, in
my transitions, and in
the emotion break, and
in any proof section
to set up the
power of the information
that's coming. For example,
this next step took
one of my clients
from me. I'm a
hundred subs to 30
,000 in a day.
What this does is
it builds trust and
it shows I'm a
business, not a YouTuber.
Then I throw in
some visual proof or
testimonials or screenshots, stripe
revenue, YouTube comments, anything
that shows this is
real. Basically, if you
make a claim, you
got to back it
up visually. The next
strategy I have here
is I talk about
my products, but don't
pitch. So in one
video, I showed the
viewers how I have
built a custom AI
for you guys. Now,
this video is a
bit odd. I kind
of rushed it out
and I didn't put
any call to action
in it at all,
but my lead magnet
signups were off the
charts because the lead
magnet was about an
AI free tool I
have and the content
was about an AI
tool. So people went
looking for it and
I got like thousands
of emails. So this
works because when I
talk about my product,
I'm creating this really
subtle us versus them
feeling and I want
the viewers to feel
FOMO that they're not
part of the us.
That's kind of it.
So if you can
get your product into
the video like I
do by showing off
all the cool things
you're doing and how
you're helping people get
results with these new
things you're trying, it's
basically like an ad.
So that's kind of
it. Now, once you've
made and posted a
video, the conversion optimization
doesn't end. So you
then want to be
looking at your rev
track data and going,
right, that did hit
the goal. And if
it did, we just
point more videos back
to it. It's kind
of it. And now
our third option for
conversion optimization is simply
optimizing for views. So
it's not so much
conversion, but if you
make a video and
you really just want
it to get views,
don't link away. YouTube
doesn't like videos that
push people off the
platform. So all you
do is you link
to another high -performing
YouTube video in your
description or one of
the ones that's converting
well for sales or
email signups. And then
you pin that in
the comments too. And
then you use your
end screen to drive
viewers to that video.
This is going to
keep the algorithm happy
with you. And that's
it. So in the
planning doc, you will
pick a goal. You
plan the content around
it. You measure the
performance using YouTube and
rev track. And then
you just point other
videos back to the
ones that win. And
over time, the goal
really is to kind
of have 20 or
more videos solving the
same three problems. Your
audience care about working
together to generate results
automatically. Now, we're going
to go much deeper
into measurement in a
later module. So don't
want to touch on
that anymore right now.
But for now, go
on to the next
video where we're going
to look at how
to plan a video.
And then after that,
we're going to move
into templates for each
format. So you can
plan from the different
types to start testing.
So let's go.